# Qingxiao (Raymond) Yuan

3912 N Vancouver Ave, Portland, 97227 (503) 839-2728, <u>yuanqingxiao@gmail.com</u> LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/raymondqxyuan Personal website: https://osuyuanqi.github.io

## **Summary:**

Seeking Full-time job opportunity in Front-end web/Software development.

-5+ years of commercial software development experience, both management and CS background

-Accomplished the Windows Phone (WP) Apps development ahead 3 weeks, rewarded the **best employee** 

-Proficient in JavaScript, jQuery, Python (have LinkedIn badge), C#, HTML5, CSS3

-Self-motivated, Collaborative, Problem solving, Fast learner, Hard working

#### **Education**

Oregon State University, Corvallis, Masters of Engineering in Computer 09/2019-12/2021 GPA: **3.86** Science

Shandong University of Science and Technology, Bachelor in Management Information 09/2008-06/2012

Shandong University of Science and Technology, Bachelor in Management Information (

# **Experience**

Sublime China Information Co., Ltd. (SCI, 5 yrs. 6 mos.)

## Web Programmer (Jan 2016 – Feb 2018)

- Motivated a team of 3 and cooperated with a mobile friendly website that more than 10,000 people use every day.
- Used JavaScript and **jQuery** for performing client side validations and signup authorization.
- Led couples of engineers learning, provided technical assistance, achieved as NO.1 JavaScript problem solver.
- Cooperated with other developers, designers and product managers to develop new features.
- Standardized all output with a new, responsive, mobile-first approach and strategy.

## Software Developer (Sep 2012 – Dec 2015)

- Founded a Window and 4 WP Apps for the company's primary services to visualize data and read industry news.
- Applied C# designed and implemented a message system for sending notifications with alerts.
- Implemented SQLite database for persistent data storage, fast data retrieval and scheduled automatic collection.
- Worked on a full software development cycle from concept through deployment with 100% on-time delivery record.
- Generated the WP Apps guidance and documents, applied for the software copyright and main procedures.
- Provided assistance to others in localizing and correcting software defects.

### **Projects**

Front-End (UX/UI Design included):

WAP Station (acquire commodity info): https://mo.sci99.com

Discord Desktop App (redesign practice), Persona, AllTrails Route Optimization (redesign practice)

Software/Mobile Development: (More: <a href="https://osuyuanqi.github.io/project\_intv.html">https://osuyuanqi.github.io/project\_intv.html</a>)

Wave (Graphics Simulation), Windmill (Graphics Simulation), SCIZhixun (get basic subscription)

Leetcode-Questions-Scraper (heavily used Python): https://github.com/osuyuanqi/Leetcode-Questions-Scraper

### **Skills Certificate**

**Hard**: Python, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, Git, Visual Studio, XAML, C#, Linux, Bootstrap, ReactJS, AngularJS, Vue.js, Express.js, Node.js, PyTorch, Pandas, NumPy, TensorFlow, OpenCV, OpenGL, Selenium, Parallel Programming, .NET, SQL, REST API, Photoshop, SEO, Heroku.

**Soft**: Team Leadership, Problem Solving, Time Management, Self-management, CITI program (ethics training) Languages: English (proficient), Chinese (native)